Tiago Patricio Santos

tiagopatriciosantos@gmail.com | (+351)965162567 | Leiria, Portugal LinkedIn: tiagopatriciosantos | Portfolio: https://tiagopatriciosantos.github.io

Summary:

Highly skilled and experienced data scientist and machine learning engineer with a background in computer engineering. Proficient in C#, SQL, and Python. Achieved Data Scientist Professional and Data Analyst Associate certifications from DataCamp, as well as a Deep Learning Specialization from DeepLearning.Al. Fluent in Portuguese and English. Possesses excellent problem-solving skills, a positive attitude, and a strong work ethic.

Skills:

- Data management, exploratory analysis, statistical analysis, experimentation, model development, coding for production environments, communication, and reporting
- Proficient in C#, SQL, and Python
- Fluent in Portuguese and English
- Excellent problem-solving skills, positive attitude, and strong work ethic

Education and Training:

- Data Scientist Professional Certification | DataCamp | Nov 2022
- Data Analyst Associate Certification | DataCamp | Sep 2022
- Data Engineer with Python Certification | DataCamp | Jul 2022
- Deep Learning Specialization | DeepLearning.Al | Feb 2022
- Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering | ESTG, Leiria, Portugal | 2007

Experience:

Machine Learning Engineer | Identify Fake Job Posting | Personal Project | Jan 2023 - Current

- Successfully developed a solution to identify fake job postings
- Conducted exploratory data analysis and utilized Scikit-learn's algorithms to evaluate the model's performance
- Demonstrated proficiency in version control tools like DagsHub and DVC, as well as experiment tracking tools like MLFlow, to create a reproducible and version-controlled data science project.
- Deployed the model as a WebAPI using FastAPI and Mogenius, showcasing an end-to-end understanding of ML development and deployment.

Software Engineer | (Freelancer) | January 2021 - Current

- Consultant for ERP Primavera
- Develop software solutions for clients

Team Leader | Trigénius S.A. | Fátima, Portugal | October 2019 - December 2020

- Managed a team of 11 in the Primavera ERP Functional department
- Project manager for software implementation projects
- Developed software solutions for clients

Software Engineer | Somoil S.A. | Luanda, Angola | October 2013 - December 2018

- Team leader of 3 in support of Primavera ERP BSS
- Analyzed and defined business processes and prepared project documentation
- Developed software solutions and trained and supported users

Software Engineer | Trigénius S.A. | Fátima, Portugal | January 2007 - October 2013

- Implemented ERP solutions, mainly SAP Business One and Primavera BSS ERP
- Analyzed and defined business processes of organizations and prepared project documentation and deadlines proposals
- Developed software solutions for clients

Languages:

• Portuguese: First Language

· English: Advanced